<document>

  <properties>
    <title>Cross Platform Music Organizer and Player</title>
    <author email="info.AT.melloware.DOT.com">Emil A Lefkof III</author>
  </properties>

  <body>
    <section name="Cross Platform Music Organizer and Player">

      <subsection name="Introduction">
      <p>
        Jukes was created for the serious music lover.  This program was created for people who rip full CD's or possibly
      their entire CD collection to their hard drive. Jukes allows you to have all of your CD's at your fingertips and play
      them like a real jukebox. Perfect for DJ's, whether in your house or for parties or whatever, spin all of your favorite tunes
      anytime you want. No more loading the files in to play them and removing them to add more to the list, now all of your CD's are
      at your disposal!
      </p>
       </subsection>

      <subsection name="History">

        <p>
          Jukes started out as Put Up Your Jukes! in 1998.  It was originally written as a Borland Delphi Windows application and has
          served nicely for many years.  However now in 2006 the software has run its course.  There is no longer support for
          many of the libraries it uses, and most of the Delphi support around the web is slowly dissapearing.  We had been 
          experiencing some problems with newer ID3 tags and the library that Put Up Your Jukes! uses for tagging is no longer
          supported.  I had never thought to rewrite it, much less rewrite it as a cross platform application because I felt the tools
          just were not there to make it as fast and stable as it is right now.   I recently started noticing some quality cross
          platform apps that did not look like Java apps such as Azureus and Eclipse.  It got me thinking I could rewrite it....
        </p>

      </subsection>
      
      <subsection name="Jukes 4.0">

        <p>
          Jukes 4.0 has been completely re-engineered after 7 years of experience using the old application.  It is now a cross
          platform application that will work on Windows, Solaris, Linux, and MacOSX.  It contains all the same great features 
          that Put Up Your Jukes had, and much much more.   See the <a href="new-features.html">New Features</a> section to read more 
          about the new features.  Or check out the <a href="screenshots.html">Screenshots</a> and see for yourself.
        </p>

      </subsection>

      <subsection name="Donate">

        <p>
          Although Jukes is open source, small financial donations are appreciated.  By supporting Melloware, you help fund the development
          (mainly development tools and internet access etc) of Melloware's Software.   To send money, simply click on the paypal icon below: 
        </p>
        <p>
        <a href="https://www.paypal.com/cgi-bin/webscr?cmd=_xclick&amp;business=elefkof%40ksmpartners%2ecom&amp;item_name=Jukes%20Donation&amp;item_number=1&amp;no_shipping=0&amp;no_note=1&amp;tax=0&amp;currency_code=USD&amp;bn=PP%2dDonationsBF&amp;charset=UTF%2d8" id="donate"><img alt="Melloware Inc." src="https://www.paypal.com/images/x-click-but04.gif"></img></a>
        </p>

      </subsection>

    </section>
 </body>
</document>