<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document>
  <properties>
    <title>Remote Connection</title>
    <author email="info.AT.melloware.DOT.com">Emil A Lefkof III</author>
  </properties>
  <body>
    <section name="Remote Connection">
       <p>
       This document describes how to connect all of your machines on you network to the same database
       and share the same music.  
       </p>
       
       <p>
       <strong>NOTE:</strong> These instructions are Windows-centric but should work on other
       platforms just in a OS specific way of sharing data.  
       </p>
      
      <subsection name="Step 1">
        <p>
          First you must share your music collection so it is available to other users on your network.
          Example, on Windows, right click on your music folder and select Properties->Sharing.
        </p>
        
        <p>
           Make sure you can see the music by connecting to that share from another machine on your network
           using the network notation.  On Windows, you would connect to <code>\\(machine name)\\music</code> where
           (machine name) was the name of your shared machine, and music is the directory shared.  NOTE: The rest of this 
           document will assume a hypothetical (machine name) called JUKEZ.
        </p>
      </subsection>
      
      <subsection name="Step 2">
        <p>
          In the Jukes use the Location Change tool in Tools->Location Change.  Change your entire database from where
          the music was located, to the network share name.  Example, if your music was in <code>C:\music</code> and you shared that folder
          on you machine named JUKEZ it would be <code>\\JUKEZ\music</code>.  You would do a Location Change and change <code>C:\</code> to <code>\\JUKES\</code>.
          This will fix your entire database to point at the files as a network share rather than hardcoded drive letter.
        </p>
        
        <p>
          Don't forget to change your Prefences->Music Directory to \\JUKEZ\music from C:\music so new albums added will be
          added with the shared directory notation.
        </p>
        
        <p>
          To check if it is correct.  Just click on an album, if it shows up in RED, then it cannot find the album.
        </p>
      </subsection>
      
      <subsection name="Step 3">
        <p>
          The next step is configuring your server.  To find out your server's IP
          address just go to a command promt and type <code>ipconfig</code>.  To get to a command prompt on Windows just
          select Start->Run and type <code>command</code>.  Typing <code>ipconfig</code> will display your IP address such as
          <strong>192.168.1.100</strong>.  Now that you have the IP address make sure the Jukes is running on the JUKEZ server.
        </p>
      </subsection>
      
      <subsection name="Step 4">
        <p>
          The next step is connecting to your server from another machine on your network.  From another machine on your
          network make sure you can see the JUKEZ server by executing <code>ping 192.168.1.100</code> from the command
          prompt.  You should see successful replies which indicates you can see that machine on the network.
        </p>
        
        <p>
           Now start the Jukes on the remote machine you are working on.   In Tools->Preferences there is a setting for Remote
           Database URL.  This defaults to <code>jdbc:hsqldb:hsql://127.0.0.1/jukes</code> which is your local machine.  You
           need to change that value to <code>jdbc:hsqldb:hsql://192.168.1.100/jukes</code> or whatever the IP address
           from Step 3 was.  This will attempt to connect to the database running on the JUKEZ server.  You may get a 
           connection error which means either the Jukes is not running on the server or for some reason you do not have
           network access.
        </p>
        
        <p>
           <strong>NOTE: </strong>Depending on your network you may be able to use the machine name instead of the IP address.  
           You can test this out by trying <code>jdbc:hsqldb:hsql://JUKEZ/jukes</code>.
        </p>
        
        <p>
           That's it!!!  Happy remoting, if all went well you should see your entire catalog and nothing should be RED.
           Any comments or suggestions for this document are welcome.
        </p>
      </subsection>
     
    </section>
    
  </body>
</document>